<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- This grammar has been deprecated - use FMPXMLRESULT instead -->
<FMPDSORESULT xmlns="http://www.filemaker.com/fmpdsoresult">
    <ERRORCODE>0</ERRORCODE>
    <DATABASE>FBR_Registry_Prototype.fp7</DATABASE>
    <LAYOUT/>
    <ROW MODID="11" RECORDID="21">
        <organizationID>EACO21</organizationID>
        <o_primary_name>Yale University </o_primary_name>
        <org_abbreviation/>
        <o_alt_name1>Yale</o_alt_name1>
        <o_alt_name2/>
        <o_alt_name3/>
        <o_address1>149 Elm Street </o_address1>
        <o_address2/>
        <o_city>New Haven</o_city>
        <o_state>CT</o_state>
        <o_postalcode>06520-1942</o_postalcode>
        <o_country>United States</o_country>
        <o_URL>http://www.yale.edu/</o_URL>
        <o_phone>(203) 432-2300 </o_phone>
        <o_email_address/>
        <o_note/>
        <o_description>Yale’s roots can be traced back to the 1640s, when colonial clergymen led an
            effort to establish a college in New Haven to preserve the tradition of European liberal
            education in the New World. This vision was fulfilled in 1701, when the charter was
            granted for a school “wherein Youth may be instructed in the Arts and Sciences [and]
            through the blessing of Almighty God may be fitted for Publick employment both in Church
            and Civil State.” In 1718 the school was renamed “Yale College” in gratitude to the
            Welsh merchant Elihu Yale, who had donated the proceeds from the sale of nine bales of
            goods together with 417 books and a portrait of King George I. Yale College survived the
            American Revolutionary War (1775–1783) intact and, by the end of its first hundred
            years, had grown rapidly. The nineteenth and twentieth centuries brought the
            establishment of the graduate and professional schools that would make Yale a true
            university. The Yale School of Medicine was chartered in 1810, followed by the Divinity
            School in 1822, the Law School in 1824, and the Graduate School of Arts and Sciences in
            1847 (which, in 1861, awarded the first Ph.D. in the United States), followed by the
            schools of Art in 1869, Music in 1894, Forestry &amp; Environmental Studies in 1900,
            Nursing in 1923, Drama in 1955, Architecture in 1972, and Management in 1974.
            International students have made their way to Yale since the 1830s, when the first Latin
            American student enrolled. The first Chinese citizen to earn a degree at a Western
            college or university came to Yale in 1850. Today, international students make up nearly
            9 percent of the undergraduate student body, and 16 percent of all students at the
            University. Yale’s distinguished faculty includes many who have been trained or educated
            abroad and many whose fields of research have a global emphasis; and international
            studies and exchanges play an increasingly important role in the Yale College
            curriculum. The University began admitting women students at the graduate level in 1869,
            and as undergraduates in 1969. Yale College was transformed, beginning in the early
            1930s, by the establishment of residential colleges. Taking medieval English
            universities such as Oxford and Cambridge as its model, this distinctive system divides
            the undergraduate population into twelve separate communities of approximately 450
            members each, thereby enabling Yale to offer its students both the intimacy of a small
            college environment and the vast resources of a major research university. Each college
            surrounds a courtyard and occupies up to a full city block, providing a congenial
            community where residents live, eat, socialize, and pursue a variety of academic and
            extracurricular activities. Each college has a master and dean, as well as a number of
            resident faculty members known as fellows, and each has its own dining hall, library,
            seminar rooms, recreation lounges, and other facilities.</o_description>
        <o_parent_org/>
        <o_legal_status>
            <DATA/>
            <DATA/>
        </o_legal_status>
        <o_legal_status_notes/>
        <o_maintenance_history_agent>parillal</o_maintenance_history_agent>
        <o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency>
        <o_eventDateTime1>11/30/2011</o_eventDateTime1>
        <o_eventDateTime2>2/15/2012</o_eventDateTime2>
        <o_eventDateTime3/>
        <o_language1>English</o_language1>
        <o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code>
        <o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script>
        <o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code>
        <o_language2/>
        <o_language2_code/>
        <o_language2_script/>
        <o_language2_script_code/>
        <o_language3/>
        <o_language3_code/>
        <o_language3_script/>
        <o_language3_script_code/>
        <o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus>
        <o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus>
        <o_source>
            <DATA>Yale University (no date). &quot;About Yale: History.&quot; Retrieved November 30,
                2011 from http://www.yale.edu/about/history.html</DATA>
            <DATA/>
            <DATA/>
        </o_source>
        <exist_date1>1701</exist_date1>
        <exist_date2/>
    </ROW>
</FMPDSORESULT>
