<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- This grammar has been deprecated - use FMPXMLRESULT instead --><FMPDSORESULT xmlns="http://www.filemaker.com/fmpdsoresult"><ERRORCODE>0</ERRORCODE><DATABASE>FBR_Registry_Prototype.fp7</DATABASE><LAYOUT></LAYOUT><ROW MODID="39" RECORDID="3"><organizationID>EACO1</organizationID><o_primary_name>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation>SIA</org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1>SI-Archives</o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1>600 Maryland Avenue, SW </o_address1><o_address2>Suite 3000 </o_address2><o_city>Washington</o_city><o_state>DC</o_state><o_postalcode>20024-2520 </o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://siarchives.si.edu/</o_URL><o_phone>(202) 633-5870</o_phone><o_email_address>osiaref@si.edu </o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>Although the first Smithsonian Secretary, Joseph Henry, had seen the need for an archives to preserve the records of the Institution, the Smithsonian Institution Archives had its real origins in 1891, when William Jones Rhees, who had been Chief Clerk since 1852, was given the title Keeper of the Archives. Rhees served in the post until his death in 1907. For the first half of the twentieth century, the administrative staff of the Office of the Secretary cared for the historical records while maintaining the current files. In 1958 John F. Jameson III was hired by the Secretary&apos;s Office to maintain the archives while also working with the current files. In 1960 Jameson was succeeded as Archivist by John DeGurse, Jr., who remained in the position until 1964. The mission of the Archives became more research-oriented in 1965, when Samuel T. Suratt was appointed Smithsonian Archivist. His hiring was accompanied by the charge to engage in the &quot;development of the Archives as a facility for historical research in American Science&quot; by making the Archives&apos; resources more readily accessible to historians through better identification, preservation, and cataloging of Smithsonian documents. Within two years the Smithsonian Institution Archives was no longer funded by the Office of the Secretary and became a separate line item in the Institution&apos;s budget. The Archives moved into new quarters within the Smithsonian Castle during Suratt&apos;s tenure. The Archives Division was comprised of three teams until FY 2007. The Records Management (RM) Team is responsible for the appraisal and acquisition of all permanent and temporary records into the Archives and its Records Center. The Team also provides records management guidance and advice to offices, and creates records disposition schedules for institutional records. The Arrangement and Description Team created descriptive tools for SIA collections, including finding aids, bibliographic records, and agency histories. The Reference Team receives visiting researchers into the Archives and answers other inquiries from remote researchers. In 2007 the Arrangement and Description Team was disbanded, and the RM Team has assumed those responsibilities. </o_description><o_parent_org>Smithsonian Institution</o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA>Federal Government, non-profit</DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>parillal</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>02-09-2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/8/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>new </o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>inProcess</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>Smithsonian Institution Archives. (February 8, 2011).  &quot;Contact Us&quot;.  Retrieved from http://siarchives.si.edu/sia/main_contact.html.</DATA><DATA>Smithsonian Institution Archives. (January 11, 2008). &quot; About SI Archives.&quot; Retrieved fromhttp://siarchives.si.edu/sia/main_about.html </DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1958</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="23" RECORDID="4"><organizationID>EACO4</organizationID><o_primary_name>National Geographic Society (U.S.) </o_primary_name><org_abbreviation>NGS</org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1>National Geographic</o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1>1145 17th Street N.W.</o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city>Washington</o_city><o_state>DC</o_state><o_postalcode>20036-4688</o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://www.nationalgeographic.com</o_URL><o_phone>(800) 647-5463</o_phone><o_email_address>mkoumane@ngs.org </o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>The National Geographic Society was established in 1888. It is one of the largest non-profit scientific and educational institutions in the world. Its interests include geography, archaeology and natural science, the promotion of environmental and historical conservation. With a mission to &quot;increase and diffuse geographic knowledge,&quot; the Society is dedicated to inspiring people to care about the planet. Its main objectives are: research and exploration, to learn about the world... education, to share that growing knowledge with members... and conservation, to encourage the protection of our planet, its people and its natural resources. Since 1888, the National Geographic Society has funded more than 9,400 expeditions all over the world. Each year it supports some 500 expeditions, explorations and research projects of scientific and environmental significance. Past and current grantees include polar explorer Robert Peary; Hiram Bingham, excavator of the lost Inca city of Machu Picchu; anthropologists Louis and Mary Leakey; mountain gorilla expert Dian Fossey; author and historian Stephen Ambrose; underwater explorer Robert Ballard; anthropologist Wade Davis; Egyptologist Zahi Hawass; marine biologist Sylvia Earle; high-altitude archaeologist Johan Reinhard; and paleontologist Paul Sereno. </o_description><o_parent_org></o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA>non-profit</DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>parillal</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>3/9/2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/14/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA> National Geographic Society. (2009). &quot;National Geographic Press Room: Fact Sheet&quot;. Retrieved from http://press.nationalgeographic.com/pressroom/index.jsp?pageID=factSheets_detail&amp;siteID=1&amp;cid=1225283738357. </DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1888</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="28" RECORDID="5"><organizationID>EACO5</organizationID><o_primary_name>National Zoological Park (U.S.) </o_primary_name><org_abbreviation>NZP</org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1>National Zoo</o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1>3001 Connecticut Ave. NW</o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city>Washington</o_city><o_state>DC</o_state><o_postalcode>20008</o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://nationalzoo.si.edu</o_URL><o_phone>(202) 633-4888 </o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>Originally conceived by S. P. Langley, Secretary of the Smithsonian, as a place in which to house endangered species and to conduct research, the National Zoological Park (NZP) was established by an Act of Congress in 1889. A National Zoological Park Commission, comprised of the Secretary of the Interior, the President of the Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia, and the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, was formed under the Act to select and purchase land for the National Zoo. One hundred and sixty-six acres in the valley of Rock Creek, located in northwest Washington, D.C., were eventually purchased for the Park. Frederick Law Olmsted, landscape architect, was consulted with regard to the design of the landscape and the location of the buildings. Copies of his drawings and sketches by his firm are presently located at the National Zoological Park.
The expenses of the NZP were to be shared by the Congress and the District of Columbia, a fact which altered Langley&apos;s vision, enlarging his purpose to one of securing a wide variety of species for the enjoyment of the District&apos;s residents. In 1890, Congress passed another Act which placed the National Zoological Park under the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian.
The first inhabitants of the Zoo were the 185 animals under the care of William Temple Hornaday, Curator of Living Animals, United States National Museum, that had been sheltered by fences behind the Smithsonian Institution Building. These animals had been shipped to Washington to be used as Hornaday&apos;s taxidermy models. Previously, those which had not been killed and preserved for the mammal collection had been shipped to the Philadelphia Zoo.
Hornaday became the first Superintendent of the Zoo, but resigned soon afterwards over differences of opinion with Langley. Frank Baker, Assistant Superintendent of the United States Life Saving Service and Professor of Anatomy at Georgetown University, was appointed Acting Manager of the NZP in 1890, and from 1893 to 1916 he held the position of Superintendent. The early history of the NZP was marked by the demands for building construction, park layout and roads, and acquisition of animals -- all on an extremely tight budget. Despite these difficulties, the Park and its animal collections began to take shape. In 1891, Dunk and Gold Dust, the Zoo&apos;s first elephants, and French, the first lion, arrived.
Upon Baker&apos;s retirement in 1916, Ned Hollister, Assistant Curator of Mammals at the United States National Museum, was appointed to succeed him. During Hollister&apos;s tenure as Superintendent, the NZP continued to operate on modest appropriations. As a result, few new animals were purchased, and housing for existing animals remained inadequate. However, the popularity of the Park continued to grow, and in 1924, 2.4 million people visited the Zoo. Superintendent Hollister died in 1924 and was succeeded by Alexander Wetmore, a biologist at the Biological Survey, United States Department of Agriculture, who served only five months before leaving to become Assistant Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution.
In 1925, William M. Mann, entomologist at the Department of Agriculture, became the fifth NZP Superintendent. The title of the NZP head administrator was changed in 1926 to that of Director, and Mann held that position until his retirement in 1956. Several major collecting expeditions helped add to the NZP animal stock during the era of the Great Depression and World War II. Included were the Smithsonian-Chrysler Fund Expedition to Tanganyika, 1926; the National Geographic Society-Smithsonian Institution Expedition to the East Indies, 1937; and the Smithsonian-Firestone Expedition to Liberia, 1940. Mann&apos;s tenure also witnessed the construction of new animal houses and support buildings, including several which were built by the Public Works Administration, a New Deal relief program.
When Mann retired in 1956, the Zoo veterinarian, Theodore H. Reed, was appointed Acting Director. He was made Director in 1958 and remained in the position until 1983. Under Reed&apos;s direction the NZP and its programs evolved rapidly. A 1962 master plan led to a series of phased renovation and construction projects. The Education-Administration Building, 1977; the William M. Mann Memorial Lion-Tiger Exhibit, 1976; and Beaver Valley, 1979, were just a few of the projects completed during Reed&apos;s tenure. The NZP benefited considerably by the creation of the Friends of the National Zoo (FONZ) in 1958. Originally concerned with capital improvements and modernization, the focus of FONZ activities changed to education by the mid-1960s. Eventually, FONZ took charge of parking, food, and souvenir concessions at the Zoo with proceeds used to augment educational work and scientific research. Several important animal acquisitions were made during the period, notably the white tigress, Mohini, in 1960, the gift of a pair of Komodo dragons from the government of Indonesia in 1964, and the arrival of a pair of giant pandas from the People&apos;s Republic of China in 1972. Programs in scientific research and conservation were developed under Reed. A Scientific Research Department was created in the mid-1960s to conduct studies on animal behavior, reproduction, and breeding. In 1975, the General Services Administration transferred over 3,000 acres of land in Front Royal, Virginia, to the Smithsonian Institution to establish the NZP&apos;s Conservation and Research Center (CRC). The goal of CRC is to conduct research on and to develop breeding programs for endangered and exotic species. Michael H. Robinson succeeded Reed as NZP Director in 1984, serving until 2000, when Lucy H. Spelman became Director, 2000-2004. Subsequent directors include David L. Evans, Acting Director, January-September 2005; John Berry, October 2005-February 2009; Steven L. Monfort, Acting Director, February 2009-February 2010; and Dennis Kelly, February 2010- .</o_description><o_parent_org>Smithsonian Institution</o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA>Federal Government, non-profit</DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>parillal</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>3/9/2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/14/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>Smithsonian National Zoological Park. &quot;About Us: History&quot;. Retrieved from  http://nationalzoo.si.edu/AboutUs/History/.</DATA><DATA>SIA AH00006 [Agency History]</DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1889</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="28" RECORDID="6"><organizationID>EACO6</organizationID><o_primary_name>Firestone Tire and Rubber Company</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation>FSNR</org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1>Firestone Liberia</o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2>Firestone Natural Rubber Company </o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3>Firestone Natural Rubber Company, LLC</o_alt_name3><o_address1>250 W. 96th St.</o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city>Indianapolis</o_city><o_state>IN</o_state><o_postalcode>46260</o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL></o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>In 1926, the then Firestone Tire &amp; Rubber Company leased 1,600 square miles of jungle in Liberia, West Africa, with the goal of producing its own rubber. By the 1920&apos;s the operation grew to employ thousands Liberians.  Currently, Firestone Liberia operates on a much smaller area of land with close to 8 million rubber trees planted on 200 square miles at its Harbel location. It is named after Firestone founder Harvey Firestone and his wife Idabelle. </o_description><o_parent_org>Firestone</o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA>for-profit</DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>parillal</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>3/10/2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/14/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>Firestone Natural Rubber Company, LLC. (2010). &quot;Firestone and Liberia – Company History&quot;.  Retrieved from http://www.firestonenaturalrubber.com/company_history.htm. </DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1926</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="23" RECORDID="7"><organizationID>EACO7</organizationID><o_primary_name>Harvard University Museum of Comparative Zoology</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation>MCZ</org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1></o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1>Harvard University</o_address1><o_address2>26 Oxford Street</o_address2><o_city>Cambridge</o_city><o_state>MA</o_state><o_postalcode>02138</o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL></o_URL><o_phone>(317) 495-2460</o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>The Museum of Comparative Zoology (MCZ) at Harvard University is a center for research and education focused on the comparative relationships of animal life. The MCZ was founded in 1859 by an act, signed into law, of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts primarily through the efforts of Louis Agassiz, a brilliant lecturer and scholar from Switzerland. The museum established and served as a training ground for professional zoologists and influenced many budding US museums through this new generation.Research at the MCZ continues to follow Agassiz’s vision to illuminate the structures of living things, their natural classification and relationship with their surroundings, while remaining a leading institution for modern zoological research. The present-day MCZ collections are comprised of approximately 21 million extant and fossil invertebrate and vertebrate specimens, which continue to be a focus of research and teaching for MCZ, Harvard and outside students and researchers. </o_description><o_parent_org>Harvard University</o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA>non-profit</DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>parillal</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>3/11/2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/14/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>Harvard University, Museum of Comparative Zoology. (2011). &quot;About MCZ.&quot; Retrieved from http://www.mcz.harvard.edu/about/index.html.</DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1859</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="14" RECORDID="8"><organizationID>EACO8</organizationID><o_primary_name>Lamont-Doherty Earth Observatory</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation></org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1>Lamont Geological Observatory</o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2>Columbia University. Lamont-Doherty Earth Observatory</o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3>Lamont-Doherty Geological Observatory</o_alt_name3><o_address1>P.O. Box 1000</o_address1><o_address2>61 Route 9W</o_address2><o_city>Palisades</o_city><o_state>NY</o_state><o_postalcode>10964-1000 </o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://www.ldeo.columbia.edu/</o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>The Lamont-Doherty Earth Observatory was established by Columbia University in 1949 as the Lamont Geological Observatory.  The observatory was named after Thomas W. Lamont (1870-1948), an alumna of Columbia University who had donated his estate to the University at his death. Name changes occurred in 1969 and 1993.  The first name change was in honor of a large donation from the Henry L. and Grace Doherty Charitable Foundation, and the second name change reflected the Observatory&apos;s &quot;growing scope of expertise.&quot;  Research conducted by the Lamont Geological Observatory encompasses the full range of earth sciences including a large oceanographic collection.  </o_description><o_parent_org>Columbia University</o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>nakasones</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>4/26/2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/14/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>revised</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>Lamont-Doherty Earth Observatory.  (n.d.).  Retrieved June 29, 2011 from the Lamont-Doherty Earth Observatory About page: http://www.ldeo.columbia.edu/about-ldeo</DATA><DATA>Lamont-Doherty Earth Observatory.  (n.d.).  Retrieved June 29, 2011 from the Lamont-Doherty Earth Observatory History if Lamont page: http://www.ldeo.columbia.edu/about-ldeo/history-lamont-0</DATA><DATA>For more information, please visit http://www.ldeo.columbia.edu/ (active as of 6/29/2011).</DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1949</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="6" RECORDID="9"><organizationID>EACO9</organizationID><o_primary_name>Smithsonian Institution</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation></org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1></o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1>1000 Jefferson Dr. SW </o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city>Washington</o_city><o_state>DC</o_state><o_postalcode>20560</o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://www.si.edu/</o_URL><o_phone>(202) 633-1000</o_phone><o_email_address>info@si.edu</o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>James Smithson (1765-1829), a British scientist, left his estate to the United States to found “at Washington, under the name of the Smithsonian Institution, an establishment for the increase and diffusion of knowledge.” The Smithsonian Institution was officially established by legislation signed by President James K. Polk on August 10, 1846, as a trust to be administered by a Board of Regents and a Secretary of the Smithsonian. Since its founding, the Smithsonian has become the world’s largest museum and research complex, with 19 museums, the National Zoo and nine research facilities.The Secretary of the Smithsonian, appointed by the Board of Regents, is the Institution&apos;s chief executive officer. Secretaries have included Joseph Henry, 1846-1878; Spencer F. Baird, 1878-1887; Samuel P. Langley, 1887-1906; Charles D. Walcott, 1907-1927; Charles G. Abbot, 1928-1944; Alexander Wetmore, 1944-1952; Leonard Carmichael, 1953-1964; S. Dillon Ripley, 1964-1984; Robert McCormick Adams, 1984-1994; Ira Michael Heyman, 1994-2000; Lawrence M. Small, 2000-2007; Cristián Samper, Acting Secretary, 2007-2008; and G. Wayne Clough, 2008 - .</o_description><o_parent_org></o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>nakasones</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>6/8/2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/14/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>SIA AH00002 [Agency History]</DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1846</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="10" RECORDID="10"><organizationID>EACO10</organizationID><o_primary_name>National Museum of Natural History (U.S.) Division of Vertebrate Paleontology </o_primary_name><org_abbreviation></org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1>United States National Museum Dept. of Vertebrate Paleontology</o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2>United States National Museum Section of Vertebrate Paleontology</o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1>10th St. and Constitution Ave., NW</o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city>Washington</o_city><o_state>DC</o_state><o_postalcode>20560</o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://paleobiology.si.edu/index.html</o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>Work in vertebrate paleontology at the Smithsonian Institution predates the formal establishment of a Department of Vertebrate Paleontology in the United States National Museum (USNM) in 1887. Joseph Leidy and E.D. Cope, among others, studied the fossil collections which had been gathered by the various government exploring expeditions and sent to the Smithsonian. With the organization of the USNM in 1880, the Department of Comparative Anatomy was given charge of the collections until the creation of the Department of Vertebrate Paleontology in 1887, with Othniel Charles Marsh as Honorary Curator. Since its creation, the present-day Division of Vertebrate Paleontology has undergone a number of organizational and title changes.
In 1894, the Department of Vertebrate Paleontology became a Section of the Department of Paleontology. The USNM reorganization of 1897 created a Division of Stratigraphic Paleontology in the Department of Geology, and Vertebrate Paleontology was made a Section of that Division. It became a separate Division in 1908, but in 1911 was again made a Section, this time of the Division of Paleontology. In 1924, this Division was renamed the Division of Stratigraphic Paleontology, and Vertebrate Paleontology again became a separate Division. In 1963, the Department of Geology was abolished as part of a reorganization in the Museum of Natural History. At that time, Vertebrate Paleontology became a Division of the newly created Department of Paleobiology.
Curators and research staff of the Division of Vertebrate Paleontology have included Othniel Charles Marsh, Honorary Curator, 1887-1899; Frederic A. Lucas, Curator, intermittently from 1889 to 1904; James William Gidley, Preparator, Custodian of Fossil Mammals, and Assistant Curator, 1905-1931; Charles W. Gilmore, Assistant Curator, Associate Curator, and Curator, 1911-1945; C. Lewis Gazin, Assistant Curator, Associate Curator, Curator, and Senior Paleobiologist, 1932-1970; David Hosbrook Dunkle, Associate Curator, 1946-1967; Peter Paul Vaughn, Associate Curator, 1957-1959; Nicholas Hotton, Associate Curator, Curator, and Curator Emeritus, 1959-1997; Clayton Edward Ray, Associate Curator, Curator, and Curator Emeritus, 1964-1997; Robert J. Emry, Associate Curator, Curator, and Curator Emeritus, 1971-2011; and Anna K. Behrensmeyer, Assistant Curator, Associate Curator, and Curator, 1981- .</o_description><o_parent_org>EACO25</o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>mathiasj</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>6/20/2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/14/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latin</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>SIA AH00049 [Agency History]</DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1887</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="7" RECORDID="11"><organizationID>EACO11</organizationID><o_primary_name>United States Dept. of Agriculture</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation>USDA</org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1></o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1>1400 Independence Ave., S.W.</o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city>Washington</o_city><o_state>DC</o_state><o_postalcode>20250</o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://usda.gov/wps/portal/usda/usdahome</o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>The United States Department of Agriculture is the United States federal executive department responsible for developing and executing U.S. federal government policy on farming, agriculture, and food. It aims to meet the needs of farmers and ranchers, promote agricultural trade and production, work to assure food safety, protect natural resources, foster rural communities and end hunger in the United States and abroad.Numerous branches of the USDA have worked closely with the United States National Museum, and later the National Museum of Natural History, since the late nineteenth century. Scientists have worked in Smithsonian facilities and many collections from research are housed in the National Museum of Natural History.</o_description><o_parent_org></o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>mathiasj</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>6/21/2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/14/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usda</DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1862</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="10" RECORDID="12"><organizationID>EACO12</organizationID><o_primary_name>National Museum of Natural History (U.S.) Pacific Ocean Biological Survey Program</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation>NMNH-POBSP</org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1>Pacific Ocean Biological Survey Program</o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2>Pacific Ocean Biological Survey</o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3>Pacific Ocean Survey</o_alt_name3><o_address1></o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city></o_city><o_state></o_state><o_postalcode></o_postalcode><o_country></o_country><o_URL></o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>The Pacific Ocean Biological Survey Program (POBSP) was initiated in 1962 when the Smithsonian Institution entered into a grant agreement with the Department of Defense. From January 1963 through June 1969 Smithsonian Institution employees undertook biological surveys in an area of the Pacific Ocean spanning the equator and extending from latitude 30 degrees north to 10 degrees south and from longitude 150 degrees east to 180 degrees west, an area dotted with clusters of islands and atolls. The major goals of the program were to learn what plants and animals occurred on the islands, the seasonal variations in their numbers and reproductive activities, and the distribution and population of the pelagic birds of that area. Emphasis was placed on the banding of birds in an effort to determine migration, distribution, and abundance of pelagic sea birds. During the six and a half years of field work 1,800,000 birds were banded; approximately 150,000 observations of pelagic birds at sea were made; and biological surveys of varying intensity were made on several islands.The principal investigator of the POBSP was Philip S. Humphrey (1926- ), who came to the Smithsonian Institution in 1962 as curator of birds. In 1964 Humphrey became chairman of the newly created Department of Vertebrate Zoology, while retaining his position as curator of birds. In 1967 he left the Smithsonian to become director of the Museum of Natural History and chairman of the Department of Zoology at the University of Kansas. However, he remained as Principal Investigator of the Survey.</o_description><o_parent_org>EAC026</o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>HunterEJ</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>6/24/2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/16/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>Record Unit 245 finding aid: http://siarchives.si.edu/collections/siris_arc_216809</DATA><DATA>SIA AH00031 [Agency History]</DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1962</exist_date1><exist_date2>1969</exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="7" RECORDID="13"><organizationID>EACO13</organizationID><o_primary_name>United States. Bureau of Biological Survey</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation></org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1>U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service</o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1></o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city></o_city><o_state></o_state><o_postalcode></o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL></o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>In 1885, Congress created an Office of Economic Ornithology in the Department of Agriculture. The office studied the food habits and migratory patterns of birds, especially those that had an effect on agriculture. This office gradually grew in responsibilities and went through several name changes until finally renamed the Bureau of Biological Survey in 1905.In addition to studying birds and mammals, the Survey&apos;s responsibilities included managing the nation&apos;s first wildlife refuges, controlling predators, enforcing wildlife laws, and conserving dwindling populations of migratory birds. The Bureaus of Fisheries and Biological Survey were transferred to the Department of the Interior in 1939. In 1940, they were combined and named the United States Fish and Wildlife Service. </o_description><o_parent_org>United States Dept. of the Interior</o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>mathiasj</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>6/27/2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/15/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>http://www.fws.gov/who/ - U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service website.</DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1885</exist_date1><exist_date2>1940</exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="15" RECORDID="14"><organizationID>EACO14</organizationID><o_primary_name>United States. Bureau of Fisheries </o_primary_name><org_abbreviation></org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1>United States Fish Commission</o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2>U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service</o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1></o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city></o_city><o_state></o_state><o_postalcode></o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL></o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>Authorization and appropriations for the United States Commission of Fish and Fisheries were passed by Congress in 1871 and Spencer F. Baird was appointed the first Commissioner. The congressional mandate was broader than Baird had originally sought. The Commission was not limited to investigations on the New England coast and no time limit was placed on its existence. This lack of specificity greatly aided the Commission&apos;s later expansion.For the first nine years of the Commission&apos;s existence, it relied on other executive agencies, particularly the Revenue Service and the Navy for vessels with which to conduct dredging and cruising operations. In 1880, construction was completed on the first Commission vessel, the Fish Hawk, and in 1883, the Albatross began operations. Most of the Fish Hawk&apos;s operations were on the Atlantic and Gulf of Mexico coasts, while the Albatross ranged as far as the Pacific coast, Bering Sea, and Japan. Other Fish Commission vessels included the Grampus, Halcyon, Danglade, and Yvonne.The original duties of the Commission were eventually extended to include fish culture, further studies of fisheries and fishery industries, and studies in fresh-water and marine biology. The Commission became part of the Department of Commerce and Labor in 1903 and its name was changed to the Bureau of Fisheries. In 1939, the Bureau was transferred to the Department of the Interior, and in 1940 was merged with the Bureau of Biological Survey to form the Fish and Wildlife Service.The U. S. Fish Commission and its successors have always maintained close ties with the Smithsonian and the United States National Museum. Baird was Assistant Secretary and Secretary of the Smithsonian while serving as Commissioner of Fish and Fisheries, and often assigned Smithsonian people to Fish Commission duties. In a number of cases, there was considerable overlap between Commission and Smithsonian work. A number of Commission staff, including Tarleton Hoffman Bean and Barton Warren Evermann, served as honorary curators for the Museum&apos;s Division of Fishes. The Museum has also served as depository for specimens collected by the Fish Commission and its successors.</o_description><o_parent_org>United States Dept. of the Interior</o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>parillal</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>6/30/2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/15/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>Record Unit 7184 finding aid: http://siarchives.si.edu/collections/siris_arc_217341</DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1903</exist_date1><exist_date2>1940</exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="11" RECORDID="15"><organizationID>EACO15</organizationID><o_primary_name>Scripps Institution of Oceanography</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation></org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1>Scripps</o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1>7835 Trade Street, Suite 100</o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city>San Diego</o_city><o_state>California</o_state><o_postalcode>92121</o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://sio.ucsd.edu/</o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>The Scripps Institution of Oceanography was founded in 1903 and joined the University of California in 1912, and is a department of University of California, San Diego. The Institution includes Birch Aquarium.  Work completed by the institution includes study of climate change, earthquakes and other natural disasters, drug-resistant diseases, water shortages, saving marine life, energy alternatives, pollution.  </o_description><o_parent_org>University of California, San Diego</o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>parillal</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>7/13/2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/14/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>Scripps Institution of Oceanography. (2012). &quot;About Scripps.&quot; Retrieved January 17, 2012 from http://sio.ucsd.edu/About/</DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1903</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="7" RECORDID="16"><organizationID>EACO16</organizationID><o_primary_name>American Museum of Natural History</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation>AMNH</org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1></o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1>Central Park West at 79th Street</o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city>New York</o_city><o_state>NY</o_state><o_postalcode>10024</o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://www.amnh.org/</o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>The American Museum of Natural History is one of the world&apos;s preeminent scientific and cultural institutions. Since its founding in 1869, the Museum has advanced its global mission to discover, interpret and disseminate information about human cultures, the natural world and the universe through a wide-ranging program of scientific research, education and exhibition.The Museum is renowned for its exhibitions and scientific collections, which serve as a field guide to the entire planet and present a panorama of the world&apos;s cultures.</o_description><o_parent_org></o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>mathiasj</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>7/15/2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/14/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>http://www.amnh.org/about/ - AMNH website</DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1869</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="8" RECORDID="17"><organizationID>EACO17</organizationID><o_primary_name>United States Navy </o_primary_name><org_abbreviation>US Navy</org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1></o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1></o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city></o_city><o_state></o_state><o_postalcode></o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://www.navy.mil/swf/index.asp</o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>The United States Navy (USN) is the naval warfare service branch of the United States Armed Forces and one of the seven uniformed services of the United States. Numerous Smithsonian scientists have participated on U.S. Navy surveys and expeditions.</o_description><o_parent_org></o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>parillal</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>8/3/2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/15/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>Michael A. Palmer (31 March 1997). &quot;A History of the Navy.&quot; Retrieved January 17, 2012 from http://www.history.navy.mil/history/history1.htm</DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1775</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="10" RECORDID="18"><organizationID>EACO18</organizationID><o_primary_name>U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service </o_primary_name><org_abbreviation></org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1></o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1></o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city></o_city><o_state></o_state><o_postalcode></o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://www.fws.gov/</o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service is a bureau within the Department of the Interior. Its mission is to work with others to conserve, protect and enhance fish, wildlife and plants and their habitats for the continuing benefit of the American people. A 1940 reorganization plan in the Department of the Interior consolidated the Bureau of Fisheries and the Bureau of Biological Survey into one agency to be known as the Fish and Wildlife Service. The Bureau of Sport Fisheries and Wildlife was created as a part of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service in the Department of the Interior on November 6, 1956, by the Fish and Wildlife Act of 1956. That act was amended on July 1, 1974 to, among other purposes, abolish the position of Commissioner of Fish and Wildlife and designate the Bureau as the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service. </o_description><o_parent_org>United States Dept. of the Interior</o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>parillal</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>8/3/2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/15/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Office of External Affair. (April 20, 2010).  &quot;About the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service&quot;. Retrieved January 17, 2012 from http://www.fws.gov/help/about_us.html</DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1956</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="11" RECORDID="19"><organizationID>EACO19</organizationID><o_primary_name>United States Antarctic Program</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation>United States Antarctic Research Program</org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1>US Antarctic Research Program</o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2>US Antarctic Program</o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1></o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city></o_city><o_state></o_state><o_postalcode></o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://www.nsf.gov/od/opp/antarct/usap.jsp</o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>Without interruption since 1956, Americans have been studying the Antarctic and its interactions with the rest of the planet. These investigators and supporting personnel make up the U.S. Antarctic Program, which carries forward the Nation&apos;s goals of supporting the Antarctic Treaty, fostering cooperative research with other nations, protecting the Antarctic environment, and developing measures to ensure only equitable and wise use of resources. The program comprises research by scientists selected from universities and other research institutions and operations and support by a contractor and other agencies of the U.S. Government. The National Science Foundation (the U.S. Government agency that promotes the progress of science) funds and manages the program. Approximately, 3,000 Americans are involved each year.The research has three goals: to understand the region and its ecosystems; to understand its effects on (and responses to) global processes such as climate; and to use the region as a platform to study the upper atmosphere and space. Antarctica&apos;s remoteness and extreme climate make field science more expensive than in most places. Research is done in the Antarctic only when it cannot be performed at more convenient locations.The program has three year-round research stations. In summer (the period of extensive sunlight and comparative warmth that lasts roughly October through February) additional camps are established for glaciologists, earth scientists, biologists, and others. Large, ski-equipped LC-130 airplanes, which only the United States has, provide air logistics. Air National Guard crews operate these planes. Helicopters, flown by a contractor, provide close support for many research teams. Tracked or wheeled vehicles provide transport over land and snow; small boats are used in coastal areas.</o_description><o_parent_org>National Science Foundation (U.S.)</o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>parillal</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>8/16/2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/15/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>National Science Foundation, Office of Polar Programs. (2008). &quot;United States Antarctic Program.&quot; Retrieved August 16, 2011, from  http://www.nsf.gov/od/opp/antarct/usap.jsp</DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1956</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="8" RECORDID="20"><organizationID>EACO20</organizationID><o_primary_name>Biltmore Herbarium</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation></org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1>Biltmore Nursery</o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1></o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city>Ashville</o_city><o_state>NC</o_state><o_postalcode></o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL></o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>Biltmore House is a mansion in Asheville, North Carolina, built by George Washington Vanderbilt II between 1889 and 1895. Vanderbilt employed Frederick Law Olmsted to design the grounds of the estate. Olmsted&apos;s vision for the Biltmore Nursery and Arboretum included provisions for a scientific Herbarium and botanical library. Part of these efforts included the publication of &quot;The Scientific Collections at Biltmore,&quot; initially established to record the existing geological, archaeological and natural resources of the estate before grading and construction permanently altered or destroyed their evidence. The Herbarium was destroyed during a flood in 1916.</o_description><o_parent_org></o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>nakasones</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>9/30/2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/15/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>Harvard University Herbarium.  Index of Botanists. Accessed October 7, 2011. http://kiki.huh.harvard.edu/databases/botanist_index.html  </DATA><DATA>http://books.google.com/books?id=5A1Y_YFaqjYC&amp;pg=PA56&amp;lpg=PA56&amp;dq=%22Biltmore+Herbarium%22&amp;source=bl&amp;ots=jIDz7yO3uH&amp;sig=Bp2fgP_ByhGFlFRYGImtuvNbBhc&amp;hl=en&amp;sa=X&amp;ei=Idc7T_rQG-HL0QGzoKGsCw&amp;ved=0CFAQ6AEwBzgK#v=onepage&amp;q=%22Biltmore%20Herbarium%22&amp;f=false</DATA><DATA>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biltmore_Estate</DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1889</exist_date1><exist_date2>1916</exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="11" RECORDID="21"><organizationID>EACO21</organizationID><o_primary_name>Yale University </o_primary_name><org_abbreviation></org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1>Yale</o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1>149 Elm Street</o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city>New Haven</o_city><o_state>CT</o_state><o_postalcode>06520-1942</o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://www.yale.edu/</o_URL><o_phone>(203) 432-2300</o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>Yale’s roots can be traced back to the 1640s, when colonial clergymen led an effort to establish a college in New Haven to preserve the tradition of European liberal education in the New World. This vision was fulfilled in 1701, when the charter was granted for a school “wherein Youth may be instructed in the Arts and Sciences [and] through the blessing of Almighty God may be fitted for Publick employment both in Church and Civil State.” In 1718 the school was renamed “Yale College” in gratitude to the Welsh merchant Elihu Yale, who had donated the proceeds from the sale of nine bales of goods together with 417 books and a portrait of King George I. Yale College survived the American Revolutionary War (1775–1783) intact and, by the end of its first hundred years, had grown rapidly. The nineteenth and twentieth centuries brought the establishment of the graduate and professional schools that would make Yale a true university. The Yale School of Medicine was chartered in 1810, followed by the Divinity School in 1822, the Law School in 1824, and the Graduate School of Arts and Sciences in 1847 (which, in 1861, awarded the first Ph.D. in the United States), followed by the schools of Art in 1869, Music in 1894, Forestry &amp; Environmental Studies in 1900, Nursing in 1923, Drama in 1955, Architecture in 1972, and Management in 1974.International students have made their way to Yale since the 1830s, when the first Latin American student enrolled. The first Chinese citizen to earn a degree at a Western college or university came to Yale in 1850. Today, international students make up nearly 9 percent of the undergraduate student body, and 16 percent of all students at the University. Yale’s distinguished faculty includes many who have been trained or educated abroad and many whose fields of research have a global emphasis; and international studies and exchanges play an increasingly important role in the Yale College curriculum. The University began admitting women students at the graduate level in 1869, and as undergraduates in 1969.Yale College was transformed, beginning in the early 1930s, by the establishment of residential colleges. Taking medieval English universities such as Oxford and Cambridge as its model, this distinctive system divides the undergraduate population into twelve separate communities of approximately 450 members each, thereby enabling Yale to offer its students both the intimacy of a small college environment and the vast resources of a major research university. Each college surrounds a courtyard and occupies up to a full city block, providing a congenial community where residents live, eat, socialize, and pursue a variety of academic and extracurricular activities. Each college has a master and dean, as well as a number of resident faculty members known as fellows, and each has its own dining hall, library, seminar rooms, recreation lounges, and other facilities.</o_description><o_parent_org></o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>parillal</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>11/30/2011</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/15/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>Yale University (no date).  &quot;About Yale: History.&quot;  Retrieved November 30, 2011 from http://www.yale.edu/about/history.html</DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1701</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="15" RECORDID="24"><organizationID>EACO24</organizationID><o_primary_name>Gorgas Memorial Laboratory </o_primary_name><org_abbreviation></org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1>Gorgas Memorial Laboratory, Panama</o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2>Laboratorio Conmemorativo Gorgas</o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3>Gorgas Memorial Laboratory of Tropical and Preventive Medicine</o_alt_name3><o_address1></o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city></o_city><o_state></o_state><o_postalcode></o_postalcode><o_country>Panama</o_country><o_URL>informatica@gorgas.gob.pa </o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note>Special note: The following heading for an earlier name is a valid AACR 2 heading: Gorgas Memorial Laboratory of Tropical and Preventive Medicine</o_note><o_description>The Gorgas Memorial Laboratory was established in Panama as part of Gorgas Memorial Institute of Tropical and Preventive Medicine in 1921, named for Dr. William Crawford Gorgas, best known for his work on yellow fever and its prevention in the Panama Canal Zone.  The facilities were run by the United States until 1990. </o_description><o_parent_org>Gorgas Memorial Institute of Tropical and Preventive Medicine</o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>parillal</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>1/31/2012</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/15/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>Spanish</o_language1><o_language1_code>spa</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2>English</o_language2><o_language2_code>eng</o_language2_code><o_language2_script>Latin</o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code>Latn</o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>inProcess</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>Instituto Conmemorativo Gorgas de Estudios de la Salud.(2010). Welcome to the portal ICGES. Retrieved January 31, 2012 from http://www.gorgas.gob.pa/</DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1921</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="4" RECORDID="25"><organizationID>EACO25</organizationID><o_primary_name>National Museum of Natural History (U.S.) Dept. of Paleobiology</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation></org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1></o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1>10th St. and Constitution Ave., NW</o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city>Washington</o_city><o_state>DC</o_state><o_postalcode>20560</o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://paleobiology.si.edu/</o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>The paleontological collections of the Smithsonian Institution were a part of the Department of Geology, United States National Museum (USNM) from 1880 until its dissolution in 1963. The Department of Paleobiology was created in 1963 as part of a reorganization in the Museum of Natural History. At that time, the Department of Geology was divided into two departments, with the Divisions of Invertebrate Paleontology and Paleobotany and Vertebrate Paleontology joined to form the Department of Paleobiology.
G. Arthur Cooper, formerly Head Curator of Geology, became the first Chairman of the Department of Paleobiology in 1963 and served until 1967. Other Chairmen have included Porter M. Kier, 1967-1972; Richard E. Grant, 1972-1977; Martin A. Buzas,1977-1982; Ian G. MacIntyre, 1982-1987; Jack W. Pierce, 1987-1993; William A. DiMichele, 1993-1998; and Richard H. Benson, 1998-2001; Douglas H. Erwin, 2001-2002; Scott Wing, 2002-2007; Conrad Christopher Labandeira, 2008-2009; and Brian T. Huber, 2010- .</o_description><o_parent_org>EACO26</o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>peterst</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>2/14/2012</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/15/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>new</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>http://www.mnh.si.edu/press_office/annual_reports/</DATA><DATA>http://paleobiology.si.edu/</DATA><DATA>SIA AH00048 [Agency History]</DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1963</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="4" RECORDID="26"><organizationID>EACO26</organizationID><o_primary_name>National Museum of Natural History (U.S.)</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation>NMNH</org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1></o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1>10th St. and Constitution Ave., NW</o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city>Washington </o_city><o_state>DC</o_state><o_postalcode>20560</o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://www.mnh.si.edu/</o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>The history of the National Museum of Natural History&apos;s collections begins with specimens collected by the United States Exploring Expedition, 1838-1842, and transferred to the Smithsonian Institution in 1858. The Smithsonian also received specimens by gift or purchase in the late 1840s. In 1850 newly appointed Assistant Secretary Spencer F. Baird donated his personal natural history collection to the Institution. During the 1850s and 1860s several expeditions which explored the American West also sent specimens to the Institution; and the dissolution of the National Institute brought additional collections in 1862. The collections were initially housed in the Smithsonian Institution Building. They were moved to the newly constructed National Museum Building (now the Arts and Industries Building) in 1881.
From the early 1880s until 1897, various departments and divisions of the United States National Museum (USNM) were responsible for zoological, botanical, geological, and anthropological collections. As a result of a major reorganization of the USNM in 1897, three Departments were created: Biology, Geology, and Anthropology, to administer the Museum&apos;s collections and research in those areas. Various curatorial divisions were established under each department. The collections were moved to a new building (now the National Museum of Natural History) devoted to natural history and anthropology in 1911. In 1947, the Department of Biology was abolished and replaced with two new Departments: Zoology and Botany.
In 1957, the USNM created two administrative subdivisions: the Museum of Natural History (MNH) and the Museum of History and Technology. The USNM was eliminated as an administrative entity in 1967, and MNH became a separate administrative unit. During 1963-1964, a major reorganization of the curatorial departments in MNH took place. The Departments of Entomology, Invertebrate Zoology, and Vertebrate Zoology were created to replace the old Department of Zoology; and the Departments of Mineral Sciences and Paleobiology were established in place of the old Department of Geology. Separate departments of Anthropology and Botany were maintained. In 1969, the Museum was renamed the National Museum of Natural History (NMNH). 
Directors of NMNH (before 1969, MNH) have included Remington Kellogg, Acting Director, 1957-1958; Albert C. Smith, 1958-1962; T.D. Stewart, 1962-1966; Richard S. Cowan, 1966-1973; Porter M. Kier, 1973-1979; James F. Mello, Acting Director, 1979; Richard S. Fiske, 1980-1985; James C. Tyler, Acting Director, 1985, 1988; Robert S. Hoffmann, 1985-1988; Frank Talbot, 1988-1994; Donald J. Ortner, Acting Director, 1994-1996; David L. Pawson, Acting Director, 1996; and Robert W. Fri, 1996-2001; J. Dennis O&apos;Connor, Acting Director, 2001-2002; Cristián Samper, 2002-2007; Paul G. Risser, Acting Director, 2007-2008; and Cristián Samper, 2008-2012.</o_description><o_parent_org></o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>peterst</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>2/15/2012</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/15/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>new</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>SIA AH00004 [Agency History]</DATA><DATA>http://www.mnh.si.edu/ and NMNH Intranet, Darwin</DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1957</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="3" RECORDID="27"><organizationID>EACO27</organizationID><o_primary_name>National Museum of Natural History (U.S.) Division of Worms</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation></org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1></o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1>10th St. and Constitution Ave., NW</o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city>Washington </o_city><o_state>DC</o_state><o_postalcode>20560</o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://invertebrates.si.edu/</o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>The Division of Worms was established on July 1, 1965, as a result of an administrative reorganization of the Department of Invertebrate Zoology. Prior to that time, the national collection of worms was under the care of the Division of Marine Invertebrates.
Professional staff of the Division of Worms have included Meredith L. Jones, Curator, 1965-1989; Marian H. Pettibone, Associate Curator, Curator, and Emeritus Zoologist, 1965-1988; W. Duane Hope, Associate Curator, Curator, Research Zoologist, and Emeritus Zoologist, 1965- ; Mary E. Rice, Associate Curator, Curator, and Emeritus Zoologist, 1965- ; Robert P. Higgins, Curator, 1978-1984; Kristian Fauchald, Associate Curator, Curator, Research Zoologist, and Emeritus Zoologist, 1979- ; Jon L. Norenburg, Research Zoologist, 1992- ; and Karen J. Osborn, Associate Curator, 2011- .</o_description><o_parent_org>EACO28</o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>peterst</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>2/16/2012</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/16/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>new</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>http://invertebrates.si.edu/</DATA><DATA>SIA AH00023 [Agency History]</DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1965</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="3" RECORDID="28"><organizationID>EACO28</organizationID><o_primary_name>National Museum of Natural History (U.S.) Dept. of Invertebrate Zoology</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation></org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1></o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1>10th St. and Constitution Ave., NW</o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city>Washington</o_city><o_state>DC</o_state><o_postalcode>20560</o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://invertebrates.si.edu/history.htm</o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>The Department of Invertebrate Zoology was created in 1965 by the separation of the Department of Zoology into vertebrate and invertebrate branches. The Divisions of Marine Invertebrates and Mollusks were under administrative control of the newly created Department of Invertebrate Zoology. On July 1, 1965, the Division of Marine Invertebrates was abolished and three new divisions were formed--Crustacea, Echinoderms, and Worms--and were joined with the existing Department of Mollusks to form the Department of Invertebrate Zoology.
Chairmen of the Department of Invertebrate Zoology have included Donald Fleming Squires, 1965-1966; Joseph Rosewater, Acting Chairman, 1966; Raymond B. Manning, 1967-1971; David L. Pawson, 1971-1975; W. Duane Hope, 1975-1981; Clyde F. E. Roper, 1981-1985; Roger F. Cressey, 1985-1988; C.W. Hart, 1988-1991; Brian Frederick Kensley, 1991-1995; Kristian Fauchald, 1995-2001; David L. Pawson, 2001-2003; Robert Hershler, 2003-2004; Jonathan A. Coddington, 2004-2005; Rafael Lemaitre, 2005-2008; Stephen Cairns, 2011; and Jon L. Norenburg, 2011- .</o_description><o_parent_org>EACO26</o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>peterst</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>2/16/2012</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/16/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>new</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>http://invertebrates.si.edu/history.htm</DATA><DATA>SIA AH00020 [Agency History]</DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1965</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="5" RECORDID="29"><organizationID>EACO29</organizationID><o_primary_name>National Museum of Natural History (U.S.) Dept. of Vertebrate Zoology</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation></org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1></o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1>10th St. and Constitution Ave., NW</o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city>Washington</o_city><o_state>DC</o_state><o_postalcode>20560</o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://vertebrates.si.edu/index.html</o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>The Department of Vertebrate Zoology was created in 1964 by the separation of the Department of Zoology into vertebrate and invertebrate branches. Vertebrate Zoology is the study of animals with backbones. Research in the department covers fishes, amphibians, reptiles, birds, and mammals. The department holds the largest collection of vertebrate specimens in the world, including historically important collections from the nineteenth and early twentieth centuries.  Research in the department provides a solid foundation of understanding for government agencies, conservation organizations, and individuals involved in fish and wildlife management.  Zoologists from two other federal agencies work so closely with colleagues and specimens at the Museum that they are permanently stationed in the building. Specialists from the National Marine Fisheries Service of the U.S. Department of Commerce focus primarily on commercially important fishes, while those from the Geological Survey of the U.S. Department of the Interior focus on amphibians, reptiles, birds, and mammals. 
Chairmen of the Department have included Philip Strong Humphrey, 1964-1968; George E. Watson, 1968-1972; Robert H. Gibbs, Jr., 1972-1978; George R. Zug, 1978-1983; W. Ronald Heyer, 1984-1987; Richard W. Thorington, 1987-1992; G. David Johnson, 1992-1999; and Lynne R. Parenti, 1999-2004; and Richard P. Vari, 2005- .</o_description><o_parent_org></o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>peterst</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>2/16/2012</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/17/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>new</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>http://vertebrates.si.edu/index.html</DATA><DATA>SIA AH00028 [Agency History]</DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1964</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="1" RECORDID="30"><organizationID>EACO30</organizationID><o_primary_name>National Museum of Natural History (U.S.) Division of Birds</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation></org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1></o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1>10th St. and Constitution Ave., NW</o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city>Washington</o_city><o_state>DC</o_state><o_postalcode>20560</o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://vertebrates.si.edu/birds/index.html</o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>The collection of Birds under the care of the Smithsonian was begun in 1850 when Spencer F. Baird, the newly appointed Assistant Secretary, came to the Institution and brought his collection of over 3,600 birds. A Department of Ornithology in the United States National Museum (USNM) was established in 1880. Its name was changed to the Department of Birds in 1881. In 1897, as a result of a reorganization of the USNM, it became the Division of Birds of the newly created Department of Biology. In 1947, the Division came under the administrative control of the Department of Zoology, and in 1964 became a division of the newly established Department of Vertebrate Zoology.
The Division of Birds houses and maintains the world&apos;s third largest bird collection with over 600,000specimens representing 80% of the approximately 9,600 known species in the world&apos;s avifauna. Division staff perform a variety of collection management activities including accessioning and cataloging new collections, preparing specimens, and loaning specimens to researchers unable to visit the Smithsonian.  In addition to the Smithsonian staff, zoologists from the Patuxent Wildlife Research Center, U.S. Geological Survey are permanently stationed in the division and work closely with colleagues and specimens at the Museum. These specialists focus primarily on North American birds.
From 1874 to 1881, Robert Ridgway was a member of the Smithsonian staff as an Assistant in Ornithology. When the Department of Birds was established, he became Curator and retained that title until his death in 1929. Other curators of the Division have included Charles Wallace Richmond, Assistant Curator and Associate Curator, 1895-1932; Joseph Harvey Riley, Assistant Curator and Associate Curator, 1928-1941; Herbert Friedmann, Curator, 1929-1960; Herbert Girton Deignan, Assistant Curator, Associate Curator, and Curator, 1940-1962; S. Dillon Ripley, Assistant Curator, 1942-1943; Walter Alois Weber, Assistant Curator, 1943-1944; Philip Strong Humphrey, Curator, 1962-1964; Richard L. Zusi, Associate Curator, Curator, and Curator Emeritus, 1964- ; Paul Slud, Associate Curator, 1965-1983; George E. Watson, Assistant Curator, Associate Curator, and Curator, 1965-1984; Roxie Laybourne, Research Associate and Curator Emeritus, 1944-1988; Storrs L. Olson, Associate Curator, Curator, and Curator Emeritus, 1975- ; and Gary R. Graves, Assistant Curator, Associate Curator, and Curator, 1986- .</o_description><o_parent_org>EACO29</o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>peterst</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>2/16/2012</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/16/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>new</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>SIA AH00030 [Agency History]</DATA><DATA>http://vertebrates.si.edu/birds/index.html</DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1880</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="2" RECORDID="31"><organizationID>EACO31</organizationID><o_primary_name>National Museum of Natural History (U.S.) Division of Fishes</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation></org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1></o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1>10th St. and Constitution Ave., NW</o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city>Washington</o_city><o_state>DC</o_state><o_postalcode>20560</o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://vertebrates.si.edu/fishes/index.html</o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>The origins of the Division of Fishes, and ichthyological work at the Smithsonian, can be traced to the arrival of Spencer F. Baird as Assistant Secretary of the Smithsonian in 1850. He brought with him extensive natural history collection including many specimens of fishes. Baird brought Charles Frederic Girard to the Smithsonian the same year and Girard remained until 1860, publishing a number of papers describing the Institution&apos;s fish collections. Theodore Gill joined the Smithsonian in 1859 to help prepare the reports of the Northwest Boundary Survey and spent much of his time working on the museum collections, although he was never an official staff member.
Ichthyological work at the Smithsonian was closely associated with that of the United States Fish Commission (USFC) which was established in 1871. In addition to his duties as Assistant Secretary, Baird was also Commissioner of Fish and Fisheries from the Commission&apos;s founding until his death in 1887. He often assigned Smithsonian staff members to Fish Commission duties, and specimens deposited by the USFC and its successor agencies have contributed importantly to the collection.
The Department of Ichthyology was established in the United States National Museum (USNM) in 1880. Its name was changed to the Department of Fishes in 1881. In 1897, as a result of a reorganization of the USNM, it became the Division of Fishes of the newly created Department of Biology. In 1947, the Division came under the administrative control of the Department of Zoology, and in 1964 became a division of the newly established Department of Vertebrate Zoology.
The fish collection at the Smithsonian&apos;s National Museum of Natural History today contains more than 388,000 catalogued lots (a lot being all the specimens of a particular species collected at a particular place at a particular time). Approximately 19,000 lots are type specimens, that is, those specimens that form the basis for species descriptions. With an estimated number of about 4 million specimens, the Smithsonian collection is the largest of its kind in the world, both in terms of quantity and diversity of coverage.
Tarleton H. Bean joined the Smithsonian as Assistant Ichthyologist in 1877 and became Curator in 1880. In 1888, he assumed full-time duties with the USFC, while retaining the title Honorary Curator until 1905.
Other curators of the Division of Fishes have included Barton A. Bean, Assistant, Aid, and Curator, 1882-1932; Barton Warren Evermann, Curator, 1906-1913; George S. Myers, Assistant Curator, 1933-1936; Leonard P. Schultz, Assistant Curator, Curator, Senior Zoologist, and Zoologist Emeritus, 1936-1986; Robert Rush Miller, Associate Curator, 1944-1948; Loren P. Woods, Associate Curator, 1948-1949; Ernest A. Lachner, Associate Curator and Curator, 1949-1981; William Ralph Taylor, Associate Curator, and Curator Emeritus, 1956-1990; Robert H. Gibbs, Jr., Associate Curator and Curator, 1963-1988; Victor Gruschka Springer, Associate Curator, Curator, and Senior Scientist Emeritus, 1963- ; Stanley H. Weitzman, Associate Curator and Curator, 1963- ; Richard P. Vari, Assistant Curator, Associate Curator, and Curator, 1980- ; G. David Johnson, Associate Curator and Curator, 1983- ; Lynne R. Parenti, Associate Curator and Curator, 1990- ; and Carole C. Baldwin, Research Zoologist, 1992- .</o_description><o_parent_org></o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>peterst</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>2/16/2012</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/16/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>new</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>http://vertebrates.si.edu/fishes/index.html</DATA><DATA>SIA AH00032 [Agency History]</DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1880</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="2" RECORDID="33"><organizationID>EACO33</organizationID><o_primary_name>National Museum of Natural History (U.S.) Division of Mammals</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation></org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1></o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2></o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1>10th St. and Constitution Ave., NW</o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city>Washington</o_city><o_state>DC</o_state><o_postalcode>20560</o_postalcode><o_country>United States</o_country><o_URL>http://vertebrates.si.edu/mammals/index.html</o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>The collection of mammals under the care of the Smithsonian was begun in 1850 when Spencer F. Baird, the newly appointed Assistant Secretary, came to the Institution and brought his private collection. The Department of Mammals was established in the United States National Museum (USNM) in 1880. In 1897, as a result of a reorganization of the USNM, it became the Division of Mammals of the newly created Department of Biology. In 1947, the Division came under the administrative control of the Department of Zoology, and in 1964 became a division of the newly established Department of Vertebrate Zoology.
The Division of Mammals houses one of the most important collections of mammals in the world. With nearly 570,000 specimens, it is by far the world&apos;s largest, roughly twice the size of the next largest mammal collection. The Division performs a variety of collection management activities including accessioning and cataloging new collections, preparing specimens, and loaning specimens to researchers unable to visit the Division. Divisional curators undertake original research programs which often utilize the collections.
Curators of the Division of Mammals have included Elliott Coues, Honorary Curator, 1880-1883; Frederick William True, Curator, 1883-1909; Gerrit S. Miller, Assistant Curator and Curator, 1898-1940; Marcus Ward Lyon, Aid and Assistant Curator, 1898-1909; Ned Hollister, Assistant Curator, 1910-1916; Remington Kellogg, Assistant Curator and Curator, 1928-1948; David H. Johnson, Associate Curator and Curator, 1941-1967; Raymond M. Gilmore, Associate Curator, 1944-1947; Henry W. Setzer, Associate Curator and Curator, 1949-1979; Charles O. Handley, Assistant Curator, Associate Curator, and Curator, 1950-1999; Richard W. Thorington, Associate Curator and Curator, 1969- ; James G. Mead, Assistant Curator, Associate Curator, and Curator, and Curator Emeritus, 1972- ; Michael D. Carleton, Assistant Curator, Associate Curator, and Curator,1979- ; and Kristopher M. Helgen, Curator, and Curator in Charge, 2008- .</o_description><o_parent_org></o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>peterst</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>2/17/2012</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/17/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>new</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>approved</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>SIA AH00033 [Agency History]</DATA><DATA>http://vertebrates.si.edu/mammals/index.html</DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1964</exist_date1><exist_date2></exist_date2></ROW><ROW MODID="3" RECORDID="34"><organizationID>EACO34</organizationID><o_primary_name>United States. Bureau of Entomology</o_primary_name><org_abbreviation></org_abbreviation><o_alt_name1>Division of Entomology</o_alt_name1><o_alt_name2>United States Department of Agriculture.  Bureau of Entomology</o_alt_name2><o_alt_name3></o_alt_name3><o_address1></o_address1><o_address2></o_address2><o_city></o_city><o_state></o_state><o_postalcode></o_postalcode><o_country></o_country><o_URL></o_URL><o_phone></o_phone><o_email_address></o_email_address><o_note></o_note><o_description>The United States Bureau of Entomology, originally the Division of Entomology, and subsequently the Bureau of Entomology and Plant Quarantine, was a unit of the United States Department of Agriculture from 1878 to 1953.</o_description><o_parent_org>EACO11</o_parent_org><o_legal_status><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_legal_status><o_legal_status_notes></o_legal_status_notes><o_maintenance_history_agent>nakasones</o_maintenance_history_agent><o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency><o_eventDateTime1>2/21/2012</o_eventDateTime1><o_eventDateTime2>2/21/2012</o_eventDateTime2><o_eventDateTime3></o_eventDateTime3><o_language1>English</o_language1><o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code><o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script><o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code><o_language2></o_language2><o_language2_code></o_language2_code><o_language2_script></o_language2_script><o_language2_script_code></o_language2_script_code><o_language3></o_language3><o_language3_code></o_language3_code><o_language3_script></o_language3_script><o_language3_script_code></o_language3_script_code><o_maintenanceStatus>new</o_maintenanceStatus><o_publicationStatus>temporary</o_publicationStatus><o_source><DATA>Geong, H. (2000). The Pink Bollworm Campaign in the South: Agricultural Quarantines and the Role of the Public in Insect Control, 1915-1930.  Agricultural History, vol. 74, no. 2, pp. 309-321.</DATA><DATA></DATA><DATA></DATA></o_source><exist_date1>1878</exist_date1><exist_date2>1953</exist_date2></ROW></FMPDSORESULT>