<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- This grammar has been deprecated - use FMPXMLRESULT instead -->
<FMPDSORESULT xmlns="http://www.filemaker.com/fmpdsoresult">
    <ERRORCODE>0</ERRORCODE>
    <DATABASE>FBR_Registry_Prototype.fp7</DATABASE>
    <LAYOUT/>
    <ROW MODID="39" RECORDID="3">
        <organizationID>EACO1</organizationID>
        <o_primary_name>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_primary_name>
        <org_abbreviation>SIA</org_abbreviation>
        <o_alt_name1>SI-Archives</o_alt_name1>
        <o_alt_name2/>
        <o_alt_name3/>
        <o_address1>600 Maryland Avenue, SW </o_address1>
        <o_address2>Suite 3000 </o_address2>
        <o_city>Washington</o_city>
        <o_state>DC</o_state>
        <o_postalcode>20024-2520 </o_postalcode>
        <o_country>United States</o_country>
        <o_URL>http://siarchives.si.edu/</o_URL>
        <o_phone>(202) 633-5870</o_phone>
        <o_email_address>osiaref@si.edu </o_email_address>
        <o_note/>
        <o_description>Although the first Smithsonian Secretary, Joseph Henry, had seen the need for
            an archives to preserve the records of the Institution, the Smithsonian Institution
            Archives had its real origins in 1891, when William Jones Rhees, who had been Chief
            Clerk since 1852, was given the title Keeper of the Archives. Rhees served in the post
            until his death in 1907. For the first half of the twentieth century, the administrative
            staff of the Office of the Secretary cared for the historical records while maintaining
            the current files. In 1958 John F. Jameson III was hired by the Secretary&apos;s Office
            to maintain the archives while also working with the current files. In 1960 Jameson was
            succeeded as Archivist by John DeGurse, Jr., who remained in the position until 1964.
            The mission of the Archives became more research-oriented in 1965, when Samuel T. Suratt
            was appointed Smithsonian Archivist. His hiring was accompanied by the charge to engage
            in the &quot;development of the Archives as a facility for historical research in
            American Science&quot; by making the Archives&apos; resources more readily accessible to
            historians through better identification, preservation, and cataloging of Smithsonian
            documents. Within two years the Smithsonian Institution Archives was no longer funded by
            the Office of the Secretary and became a separate line item in the Institution&apos;s
            budget. The Archives moved into new quarters within the Smithsonian Castle during
            Suratt&apos;s tenure. The Archives Division was comprised of three teams until FY 2007.
            The Records Management (RM) Team is responsible for the appraisal and acquisition of all
            permanent and temporary records into the Archives and its Records Center. The Team also
            provides records management guidance and advice to offices, and creates records
            disposition schedules for institutional records. The Arrangement and Description Team
            created descriptive tools for SIA collections, including finding aids, bibliographic
            records, and agency histories. The Reference Team receives visiting researchers into the
            Archives and answers other inquiries from remote researchers. In 2007 the Arrangement
            and Description Team was disbanded, and the RM Team has assumed those responsibilities. </o_description>
        <o_parent_org>Smithsonian Institution</o_parent_org>
        <o_legal_status>
            <DATA>Federal Government, non-profit</DATA>
            <DATA/>
        </o_legal_status>
        <o_legal_status_notes/>
        <o_maintenance_history_agent>parillal</o_maintenance_history_agent>
        <o_maintenance_agency>Smithsonian Institution Archives</o_maintenance_agency>
        <o_eventDateTime1>02-09-2011</o_eventDateTime1>
        <o_eventDateTime2>2/8/2012</o_eventDateTime2>
        <o_eventDateTime3/>
        <o_language1>English</o_language1>
        <o_language1_code>eng</o_language1_code>
        <o_language1_script>Latin</o_language1_script>
        <o_language1_script_code>Latn</o_language1_script_code>
        <o_language2/>
        <o_language2_code/>
        <o_language2_script/>
        <o_language2_script_code/>
        <o_language3/>
        <o_language3_code/>
        <o_language3_script/>
        <o_language3_script_code/>
        <o_maintenanceStatus>new </o_maintenanceStatus>
        <o_publicationStatus>inProcess</o_publicationStatus>
        <o_source>
            <DATA>Smithsonian Institution Archives. (February 8, 2011). &quot;Contact Us&quot;.
                Retrieved from http://siarchives.si.edu/sia/main_contact.html.</DATA>
            <DATA>Smithsonian Institution Archives. (January 11, 2008). &quot; About SI
                Archives.&quot; Retrieved fromhttp://siarchives.si.edu/sia/main_about.html </DATA>
            <DATA/>
        </o_source>
        <exist_date1>1958</exist_date1>
        <exist_date2/>
    </ROW>
</FMPDSORESULT>
